# Federico Rossi | Software Engineer

reddyfede@gmail.com | LinkedIn | GitHub | Portfolio

#### **SUMMARY**

I am a Software Engineer with a background in Industrial Engineering.

In my previous role I carried out Business Analysis and Quality Assurance working closely with software suppliers to implement new software for the factory. This has provided me the experience necessary to liaise with clients and suppliers throughout a full software life cycle.

#### **SKILLS**

Languages: HTML | CSS | JavaScript | Python | SQL | EJS

Libraries and Framework: Node.js | React.js | Express.js | Django | Bootstrap | Tailwind

Databases: PostgreSQL | MongoDB

Utilities: Git | GitHub | CLI

Various: Project Management | Business Analysis | Quality Assurance | Team Management

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## **Digital Transformation Manager**

Sarezzo, Italy

Ottoman | Turnery | Industrial Engineering

2020 - 2023

- Managed new projects for the company computerization and automation.
- Handled the 4.0 transformation of the factory: implemented new solutions for the turnery doing process
  analysis, creating wireframes and documentation for software suppliers, working hands in hands with them
  during the development process and testing in each stage, supporting and training the factory staff after
  deployment
- Scheduled the production orders for 44 production machines.
- Assigned daily tasks to 10 operators.
- Managed and maintained the Quality Control System.
- Maintained the existing IT infrastructure: defined procedures for the use of company software, offered first level IT support.

#### **Technical Department**

Italy

OFAR, Franchini Acciai | Forge | Industrial Engineering

2018 - 2020

- Analyzed client orders and specifications to ensure product feasibility.
- Engineered production cycle based on client requirements.
- Created and managed the status of production orders.

#### **EDUCATION**

## **General Assembly**

Online

July 2023 - October 2023

Software Engineering Immersive Bootcamp

Full-stack software engineering immersive student in an intensive, 12-weeks, 480+ hour program focused on product development fundamentals, object-oriented programming, MVC frameworks, data modeling, and team

# collaboration strategies. Developed a portfolio of individual and group projects.

# Universitá degli studi eCampus

Italy

Bachelor Degree in Management Engineering

2022

#### **CODING PROJECTS**

**Task flow |** TaskFlow is an application to manage your team work. It allows Team Leaders to create and assign tasks to the team according to the availability. Team members can view their daily tasks on a gantt chart. Roles: Planning, UI Design, Frontend, Backend | 10 days project | Live | Github

- Task management with Trello, ERD and Concept Design with Figma.
- Extra Features: interactive gantt to display the daily tasks.
- Tech used: Frontend: React; Backend: Django; DB: PostgreSQL, Style: Styled-Components.

**Event.ly** | Event.ly is a map-based MERN application for finding and creating events to connect with people in your local community. Created as a 10 days pair programming project at GA Software Engineering Immersive Bootcamp. Roles: Planning, UI Design, Frontend, Backend | 10 days project | <u>Live</u> | <u>Github</u>

- Task management with Trello, ERD and Concept Design with Figma.
- Created application with a mobile-first approach and styled using the CSS framework Tailwind.
- Made RESTful API calls to an Express, MongoDB, Node.js backend handling all CRUD operations, tested all backend routes during development using Postman.
- Extra Features: Leaflet map, 0Auth for secure user authentication, Unsplash API to retrieve custom pictures, Bing Maps API for reverse geocoding.
- Tech used: Frontend: React; Backend: Express.js, Node.js; DB: MongoDB; Style: Tailwind, DaisyUI.

**Little Italy Pizza** | Little Italy Pizza is a MEN stack web application for a fictitious pizza shop. Created as a weeklong pair programming project at GA Software Engineering Immersive Bootcamp.

Roles: Planning, UI Design, Frontend, Backend | Week-long project | Live | Github

- Extra Features: Animation with CSS framework Bootstrap.
- Tech used: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Backend: Express.js, Node.js; DB: MongoDB; Style: Bootstrap.

#### **SPOKEN LANGUAGES**

Italian | English

### **VOLUNTEER WORK**

Founding memberGhedi, ItalyPerSampre2014-2020

Charity-event planning in memory of our friend Sam.

EducatorGhedi, ItalyOratorio San Giovanni Bosco2014-2017

Responsible for planning and delivering activities and weekly meetings to a group of teenagers.